<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection><source>PMC</source><date>20140719</date><key>BioCBioGRID.key</key><document><id>10366597</id><passage><infon key="article-id_pmc">2133144</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">10366597</infon><infon key="fpage">1251</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="journal-title">The Journal of Cell Biology</infon><infon key="kwd">Aip1 cofilin actin cytoskeleton Saccharomyces cerevisiae</infon><infon key="lpage">1264</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Rodal;given-names:Avital A.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tetreault;given-names:Jonathan W.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lappalainen;given-names:Pekka</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Drubin;given-names:David G.</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Amberg;given-names:David C.</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">145</infon><infon key="year">1999</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Aip1p Interacts with Cofilin to Disassemble Actin Filaments </text><annotation id="G1_1"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">855117</infon><location offset="0" length="5"/><text>Aip1p</text></annotation><annotation id="G2_1"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">850676</infon><location offset="21" length="7"/><text>Cofilin</text></annotation><annotation id="G3_1"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">853528</infon><location offset="44" length="5"/><text>Actin</text></annotation><annotation id="E1"><infon key="type">PPImention</infon><location offset="0" length="59"/><text>Aip1p Interacts with Cofilin to Disassemble Actin Filaments</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>61</offset><text>Actin interacting protein 1 (Aip1) is a conserved component of the actin cytoskeleton first identified in a two-hybrid screen against yeast actin. Here, we  report that Aip1p also interacts with the ubiquitous actin depolymerizing factor cofilin. A two-hybrid-based  approach using cofilin and actin mutants identified residues necessary for the interaction of actin, cofilin, and  Aip1p in an apparent ternary complex. Deletion of the  AIP1 gene is lethal in combination with cofilin mutants  or act1-159, an actin mutation that slows the rate of actin filament disassembly in vivo. Aip1p localizes to cortical actin patches in yeast cells, and this localization is  disrupted by specific actin and cofilin mutations. Further, Aip1p is required to restrict cofilin localization to  cortical patches. Finally, biochemical analyses show that  Aip1p causes net depolymerization of actin filaments  only in the presence of cofilin and that cofilin enhances  binding of Aip1p to actin filaments. We conclude that  Aip1p is a cofilin-associated protein that enhances the  filament disassembly activity of cofilin and restricts cofilin localization to cortical actin patches.</text><annotation id="G1_2"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">855117</infon><location offset="230" length="5"/><text>Aip1p</text></annotation><annotation id="G1_3"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">855117</infon><location offset="443" length="5"/><text>Aip1p</text></annotation><annotation id="G1_4"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">855117</infon><location offset="645" length="5"/><text>Aip1p</text></annotation><annotation id="G1_5"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">855117</infon><location offset="789" length="5"/><text>Aip1p</text></annotation><annotation id="G1_6"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">855117</infon><location offset="903" length="5"/><text>Aip1p</text></annotation><annotation id="G1_7"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">855117</infon><location offset="1027" length="5"/><text>Aip1p</text></annotation><annotation id="G1_8"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">855117</infon><location offset="1071" length="5"/><text>Aip1p</text></annotation><annotation id="G2_2"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">850676</infon><location offset="299" length="7"/><text>cofilin</text></annotation><annotation id="G2_3"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">850676</infon><location offset="343" length="7"/><text>cofilin</text></annotation><annotation id="G2_4"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">850676</infon><location offset="429" length="7"/><text>cofilin</text></annotation><annotation id="G2_5"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">850676</infon><location offset="538" length="7"/><text>cofilin</text></annotation><annotation id="G2_6"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">850676</infon><location offset="761" length="7"/><text>cofilin</text></annotation><annotation id="G2_7"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">850676</infon><location offset="819" length="7"/><text>cofilin</text></annotation><annotation id="G2_8"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">850676</infon><location offset="981" length="7"/><text>cofilin</text></annotation><annotation id="G2_9"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">850676</infon><location offset="998" length="7"/><text>cofilin</text></annotation><annotation id="G2_10"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">850676</infon><location offset="1082" length="7"/><text>cofilin</text></annotation><annotation id="G2_11"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">850676</infon><location offset="1161" length="7"/><text>cofilin</text></annotation><annotation id="G2_12"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">850676</infon><location offset="1183" length="7"/><text>cofilin</text></annotation><annotation id="G3_2"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">853528</infon><location offset="128" length="5"/><text>actin</text></annotation><annotation id="G3_3"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">853528</infon><location offset="201" length="5"/><text>actin</text></annotation><annotation id="G3_4"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">853528</infon><location offset="271" length="5"/><text>actin</text></annotation><annotation id="G3_5"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">853528</infon><location offset="355" length="5"/><text>actin</text></annotation><annotation id="G3_6"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">853528</infon><location offset="422" length="5"/><text>actin</text></annotation><annotation id="G3_7"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">853528</infon><location offset="571" length="5"/><text>actin</text></annotation><annotation id="G3_8"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">853528</infon><location offset="609" length="5"/><text>actin</text></annotation><annotation id="G3_9"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">853528</infon><location offset="673" length="5"/><text>actin</text></annotation><annotation id="G3_10"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">853528</infon><location offset="751" length="5"/><text>actin</text></annotation><annotation id="G3_11"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">853528</infon><location offset="940" length="5"/><text>actin</text></annotation><annotation id="G3_12"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">853528</infon><location offset="1036" length="5"/><text>actin</text></annotation><annotation id="G3_13"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">853528</infon><location offset="1216" length="5"/><text>actin</text></annotation><annotation id="G4"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">855117</infon><location offset="61" length="27"/><text>Actin interacting protein 1</text></annotation><annotation id="G5_1"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">855117</infon><location offset="90" length="4"/><text>Aip1</text></annotation><annotation id="G5_2"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">855117</infon><location offset="498" length="4"/><text>AIP1</text></annotation><annotation id="G6"><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="GeneID">Not Available</infon><location offset="558" length="8"/><text>act1-159</text></annotation><annotation id="O1_1"><infon key="type">Organism</infon><infon key="OrganismID">4932</infon><location offset="195" length="5"/><text>yeast</text></annotation><annotation id="O1_2"><infon key="type">Organism</infon><infon key="OrganismID">4932</infon><location offset="690" length="5"/><text>yeast</text></annotation><annotation id="E2"><infon key="type">PPImention</infon><location offset="208" length="98"/><text>Here, we  report that Aip1p also interacts with the ubiquitous actin depolymerizing factor cofilin.</text></annotation><annotation id="E3"><infon key="type">PPImention</infon><location offset="308" length="172"/><text>A two-hybrid-based  approach using cofilin and actin mutants identified residues necessary for the interaction of actin, cofilin, and  Aip1p in an apparent ternary complex.</text></annotation><annotation id="E4"><infon key="type">PPIevidence</infon><location offset="308" length="172"/><text>A two-hybrid-based  approach using cofilin and actin mutants identified residues necessary for the interaction of actin, cofilin, and  Aip1p in an apparent ternary complex.</text></annotation><annotation id="E5"><infon key="type">GIevidence</infon><location offset="481" length="163"/><text>Deletion of the  AIP1 gene is lethal in combination with cofilin mutants  or act1-159, an actin mutation that slows the rate of actin filament disassembly in vivo.</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1233</offset><text>The actin cytoskeleton plays diverse roles in the cell,  mediating such processes as endocytosis, exocytosis,  cell motility, cell polarity, and cytokinesis in a spatially and temporally controlled manner. Each of these  processes requires the regulation of specific dynamic properties and spatial organization of actin filaments by a subset of a large collection of actin-binding proteins. To determine how actin and associated proteins function together  to control morphogenetic events, it will be important to  determine how actin-associated proteins are sorted to different structures of the cytoskeleton, and how the combined actions of different actin-associated proteins affect  cytoskeleton dynamics in these different structures.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1973</offset><text>Saccharomyces cerevisiae presents excellent opportunities for the study of combined effects of actin-associated  proteins on actin assembly and organization both in vivo  and in vitro. The actin cytoskeleton of S. cerevisiae is organized into polarized cortical patches and cytoplasmic bundles of actin filaments aligned along the mother-daughter  cell axis (Adams and Pringle, 1984; Amberg, 1998). Little  is known about how actin-binding proteins are sorted between different compartments of the cytoskeleton, or  whether they themselves are responsible for forming these  specialized actin networks.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2578</offset><text>We previously described a two-hybrid approach for  characterizing interactions of actin-binding proteins with  yeast actin (Amberg et al., 1995a). We used this system  to identify yeast actin-associated proteins and examined  their ability to interact with 35 clustered-charged-to-alanine mutants of actin. Those mutations that disrupt the  binding of a particular ligand can identify regions of the  actin surface important for a given interaction and can delineate an interaction footprint when displayed on the  structure of actin. Actin interacting protein 1 (Aip1p),1  identified in our two-hybrid analysis using actin as bait,  had a very distinct interaction footprint on actin subdomains III and IV. We report here that in addition to interacting with actin, Aip1p also associates with the small actin-binding protein cofilin.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3415</offset><text>Members of the cofilin/actin depolymerizing factor family are conserved actin monomer and filament binding  proteins that induce actin filament disassembly (for review  see Moon and Drubin, 1995). Yeast cofilin is 40% identical in sequence to mammalian cofilin/actin depolymerizing  factor; the gene is essential in yeast and the gene product  localizes to cortical actin patches (Moon et al. 1993). Recently, two advances have led to a greater understanding  of cofilin function in yeast: (1) A synoptic set of cofilin mutants was constructed by alanine scanning mutagenesis  (Lappalainen and Drubin, 1997) and (2) the structure of  yeast cofilin was determined (Federov at al. 1997).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4101</offset><text>In this report, we have used this large set of genetic and  structural tools in conjunction with classical biochemical  and cell biological analyses to gain insight into the function of the interactions between Aip1p, cofilin, and actin.  We found that Aip1p mediates the restriction of cofilin to  cortical actin patches and that purified Aip1p has dramatic  effects on cofilin's activity in vitro. Our results suggest that  these two proteins interact in vivo to regulate actin dynamics.</text><annotation id="E6"><infon key="type">PPImention</infon><location offset="4101" length="237"/><text>In this report, we have used this large set of genetic and  structural tools in conjunction with classical biochemical  and cell biological analyses to gain insight into the function of the interactions between Aip1p, cofilin, and actin.</text></annotation><annotation id="E7"><infon key="type">PPIevidence</infon><location offset="4101" length="237"/><text>In this report, we have used this large set of genetic and  structural tools in conjunction with classical biochemical  and cell biological analyses to gain insight into the function of the interactions between Aip1p, cofilin, and actin.</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>4591</offset><text>Materials and Methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>4613</offset><text>Yeast Strains, Media, and Genetic Methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4655</offset><text>Yeast strains are listed in Table I. FY23 and FY86 were provided by Fred  Winston (Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA). Y187 and Y190 were  provided by Steve Elledge (Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, TX).  DDY319, DDY321, DDY760, and DDY496 were constructed as described (Holtzman et al., 1993, 1994; Moon et al., 1993). Standard methods  were employed for growth, sporulation, and tetrad dissection of yeast  (Rose et al., 1989). Yeast transformations were performed by electroporation (Becker and Guarente, 1991) or by lithium acetate (Rose et al., 1989).  The medium for two-hybrid analysis was synthetic medium plus dextrose  supplemented with adenine to 10 mug/ml and 3,5-amino-triazole (3-AT)  (Sigma Chemical Co.) at 25, 50, or 100 mM. </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>5403</offset><text>Plasmid Construction and DNA Manipulations</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5446</offset><text>Plasmid pRB2247 was constructed by isolating a 1.4-kb product of a BglII  partial digest of plasmid pRB2248 and cloning this fragment into the  BamHI site of plasmid pGEX-5X-3 (Pharmacia Biotech, Inc.) such that  the AIP1 gene was in frame with the glutathione-S-transferase (GST)  reading frame. Plasmid pRB2251 was constructed by subcloning a 2.2-kb  ClaI fragment from AIP1 genomic clone pRB2249 into YCp50 such that  AIP1 and bla transcription is divergent. The deletion allele of AIP1 was  constructed by double fusion PCR and has been described elsewhere  (Amberg et al., 1995b).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6032</offset><text>Plasmids encoding fusions of the GAL4 DNA binding domain (DBD)  to SNF1 (pSE1112), the GAL4 DBD to lamin (pAS1-lamin), and the  GAL4 activation domain (AD) to SNF4 (pSE1111) were provided by  Steve Elledge. The construction of the plasmids carrying fusions of the actin-alanine scan alleles to the Gal4 DBD, a fusion of the GAL4 DBD to  ACT1 (pRB1516 also known as pDAb7), a fusion of the GAL4 AD to  ACT1 (pAIP70), and a fusion of the GAL4 AD to AIP1 (pRB2248) previously were described elsewhere (Amberg et al., 1995a). The plasmid encoding a fusion of the GAL4 DBD to AIP1 (pDAb189) was constructed  by removing the AIP1 open reading frame from pRB2248 as a BglII partial digest and cloning it into the BamHI site of plasmid pRB1516 (Amberg et al., 1995a) (a Cen version of pAS1-CYH2) so that the AIP1 open  reading frame is in frame with that of the GAL4 DBD. The construct encoding a fusion of the GAL4 AD to ABP1 (pDAb20) was constructed by  excising the ABP1 open reading frame from plasmid pRB1199 (Drubin et al.,  1988) as a 1.9-kb XhoI-EcoRI fragment, blunting the EcoRI site with T4  DNA polymerase and cloning into plasmid pACTII (gift of Steve Elledge)  that had been cut with XhoI and SalI in which the SalI site had been made  blunt with T4 DNA polymerase. The resulting construct expresses all but  the first 11 amino acids of Abp1p fused to Gal4p.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7399</offset><text>The constructs encoding fusions of the cofilin mutants to the Gal4p AD  (used for the footprinting studies) were constructed by PCR into plasmid  pACTII. The cofilin mutant and wild-type alleles were amplified off plasmids (Lappalainen et al., 1997) using primers DAo-COF1-1 (5'-cgcgccatggaacaaaagatgtctagatct-3') and DAo-COF1-2 (5'-cggaattcaccttaatgagaaccagcgcc-3') and vent polymerase (New England Biolabs Inc.). Subcloning  of cof1-4 required the use of the special primer DAo-COF1-3 (5'-cgcgccatggaacaaaagatgtctagagct-3') in the place of primer DAo-COF1-1. The  PCR products were cut with NcoI and EcoRI and cloned into similarly cut  pACTII. Each construct was cloned and tested in duplicates generated  from separate PCR reactions. When possible, constructs were confirmed  by a BbvI digest. Plasmid pACTII-COF1 was made by PCR amplification  of the COF1 open reading frame with oligonucleotides PL70 (5'-gcgcgccatggggtctagatctggtgttgctgttgc-3') and PL76.2 (5'-gcgcgcggatccttaatgagaaccagcgcctctgc-3'), digestion of the PCR product with NcoI-BamHI, and  subcloning of this insert in frame into similarly digested pACTII.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8545</offset><text>To express Aip1p as a GST fusion protein in yeast, primers ARP1 (5'-gcgcgggatccatgtcatctatctctttgaaggaa-3') and ARP3 (5'-cgcgccggccgctcactcgaggacaacattccacct-3') were used to amplify the AIP1 open reading frame  from genomic DNA. This PCR product was cleaved with BamHI and  EagI and cloned into similarly cut pEG(KT) (Mitchell et al., 1993) to  make plasmid pAR3.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8918</offset><text>To express Aip1p for in vitro translation, primers ARP16 (5'-gcgcgcacatgtatgtcatctatctctttgaaggaa-3') and ARP4 (5'-gcgcgaagctttcactcgaggacaacattccacct-3') were used to amplify the AIP1 open reading frame from  genomic DNA. This PCR product was cleaved with AflIII and HindIII  and cloned into pBAT4 (Peranen et al., 1996) cut with NcoI and HindIII  to make plasmid pAR20.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>9299</offset><text>Protein Purification and Antibody Production</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9344</offset><text>Aip1-GST fusion protein for antibody production was purified from  bacterial strain UT5600 (Delta[ompT-fepA] leu proC trpE) (provided by S.  Gottesman, National Cancer Institute, Bethesda, MD) carrying plasmid  pRB2247 by standard methods (Smith and Johnson, 1988; GST Gene Fusion System manual, Pharmacia Biotech, Inc.). Antibodies were raised in  three New Zealand white rabbits by injection of 100 mug GST-Aip1 in 1 ml  of adjuvant (RIBI ImmunoChem Research Inc.), three times at 2-wk intervals. 2 wk after the last boost, the animals were exsanguinated. Anti-Aip1 antibodies were affinity-purified on columns to which GST-Aip1p  had been conjugated by standard methods (Harlow and Lane, 1988). Purified antibodies were concentrated on a Centriplus concentrator (Amicon  Inc.).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10122</offset><text>Yeast actin was purified as described previously (Goode et al., 1999).  However, the formamide eluate from the DNaseI column was dialyzed  overnight against three changes of G buffer (5 mM Tris, pH 7.5, 0.2 mM  ATP, 0.2 mM DTT, 0.2 mM CaCl2), and concentrated to 2 ml in Centriprep 10 devices (Amicon, Inc.). The actin was polymerized by adding  initiation salts to a final concentration of 100 mM KCl, 2 mM MgCl2, and  incubating for 2 h at room temperature. Residual actin-binding proteins  were stripped from F-actin at this point by slowly adding KCl to 0.6 M and  further incubating for 30 min. The polymerized actin was pelleted at  80,000 rpm for 30 min at room temperature in a TLA100.3 rotor (Beckman Instruments, Inc.). The pelleted actin was resuspended in G buffer to  a final concentration of 50 muM and dialyzed against three changes of 2 liters of G buffer before it was frozen in liquid N2 and stored at -80 C. Cofilin was purified as a GST-fusion protein from Escherichia coli and subsequently cleaved from GST by thrombin digestion as described previously  (Lappalainen et al., 1997).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11228</offset><text>Aip1p was purified from the yeast strain DDY130 (carrying the plasmid pAR3) as a GST fusion protein under the control of the GAL promoter. 4 liters of cells were grown at 30 C in synthetic medium with 2%  dextrose and without uracil or leucine to an OD of 1.0 at 600 nm, harvested by centrifugation, and resuspended in 4 liters of synthetic medium  with 2% glycerol and without uracil or leucine. After an overnight incubation at 30 C to derepress the galactose promoter, cells were again harvested and resuspended in 4 liters of rich medium with 2% galactose. The  cultures were induced for 8 h at 30 C before cells were once again harvested, washed twice with 100 ml water, resuspended in 10 ml water, frozen as 50-mul pellets in liquid N2, and stored at -80 C. Yeast pellets were  lysed in liquid N2 in a Waring blender and thawed in PBS to a final concentration of 1x, with 1 mM PMSF and 0.5 mug/ml each of antipain, leupeptin, pepstatin A, chymostatin, and aprotin. The lystate was cleared first  by spinning at 17,000 g in a Dupont GSA rotor. The supernatant from this  spin was cleared by spinning at 50,000 rpm for 50 min in a Beckman 70Ti  rotor. This high speed supernatant was dialyzed overnight against PBS  and passed twice over a column with a 4-ml bed of glutathione agarose  beads (Sigma Chemical Co.). The column was washed five times with PBS  and incubated with thrombin (5 U/ml; Sigma Chemical Co.) overnight at  room temperature to cleave the Aip1p from the GST. The column was  washed with 8 ml 50 mM Hepes, pH 7.2, 50 mM KCl, and the flow-through was concentrated to 2 ml and loaded onto a 1-ml mono-Q anion  exchange column (Pharmacia Biotech Inc.). A linear salt gradient from  100 to 400 mM KCl was applied to the column and peak fractions containing Aip1p were concentrated to 15 muM, frozen in liquid N2, and stored at  -80 C.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>13093</offset><text>Two-Hybrid Analyses</text><annotation id="E8"><infon key="type">PPIevidence</infon><location offset="13093" length="19"/><text>Two-Hybrid Analyses</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13113</offset><text>In all cases, two-hybrid analyses were performed by mating strain Y190  carrying constructs encoding fusions to the Gal4 DBD, to strain Y187 carrying constructs encoding fusions to the Gal4 AD. Transformants were  lined, spotted, or spread as lawns on selective medium, synthetic complete  medium lacking Trp (SC-TRP) or DBD fusions and synthetic complete  medium lacking Leu (SC-LEU) for AD fusions. Mating was carried out  by replica plating the Y190 and Y187 derivatives together onto yeast extract/peptone/dextrose medium-plates, incubating at 30 C for 24 h, selecting the mated cells on SC-TRP,-LEU. The selected diploids, carrying both  DBD and AD fusion constructs, were replica plated to media containing  25, 50, and 100 mM 3-AT (Sigma Chemical Co.) and incubated at 25 C.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>13899</offset><text>Microscopy</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13910</offset><text>Immunofluorescence was performed by standard protocols using a methanol/acetone fixation (Pringle et al., 1991). Affinity-purified anti-Aip1p antibody was used at a dilution of 1:100. Affinity-purified rabbit anticofilin  was used at 1:100. Guinea pig antiactin antisera (animal 2) (Mulholland et al.,  1994) was used at 1:2,000. For Aip1p localization, FITC-conjugated goat  anti-rabbit IgG (Organon Teknika Corp.) was used at 1:1,000 and  rhodamine-conjugated goat anti-guinea pig (Organon Teknika Corp.)  was used at 1:1,000. For Aip1p localization in wild-type and act1-111  strains, rhodamine-conjugated goat anti-rabbit IgG (Cappel; ICN Biomedicals) was used at 1:1,000. For cofilin localization in DAY30 and  DDY1264 FITC-conjugated goat anti-rabbit IgG (Cappel; ICN Biochemicals) was used at 1:1,000 and rhodamine-conjugated goat anti-guinea pig  IgG (Cappel; ICN Biochemicals) was used at 1:1,000.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>14827</offset><text>Actin Filament Sedimentation Assay</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14862</offset><text>To evaluate actin filament sedimentation in the presence of Aip1p and  cofilin, 3.75 muM actin was polymerized at room temperature in F-buffer  (5 mM Tris, pH 7.5, 0.7 mM ATP, 0.2 mM CaCl2, 2 mM MgCl2, 100 mM  KCl, 0.2 mM DTT). After 45 min, polymerized actin (final concentration,  2.5 muM) was added to variable concentrations of Aip1p (final concentration, 0.012-0.5 muM) and/or cofilin (final concentration, 0.125-0.5 muM) in  F-buffer. The reactions were incubated at room temperature for 20 min  and centrifuged at 90,000 rpm for 20 min at 23 C in a TLA100 rotor  (Beckman Instruments) to pellet the actin filaments. Equal proportions of  the pellets and supernatants were fractionated on 12% SDS-PAGE gels  and proteins were visualized by Coomassie blue staining. Protein levels  were quantified using NIH Image software.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>15696</offset><text>F-Actin Binding Assay</text><annotation id="E9"><infon key="type">PPIevidence</infon><location offset="15696" length="21"/><text>F-Actin Binding Assay</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15718</offset><text>To test the cofilin dependence of Aip1p binding to F-actin, variable concentrations of yeast F-actin were incubated for 20 min at 25 C with  equimolar amounts of cofilin or control buffer. [35S]Methionine-labeled in  vitro-translated (TNT quick coupled transcription/translation; Promega  Corp.) Aip1p from plasmid pAR20 was incubated for 20 min with the cofilin-F-actin and pelleted for 20 min at 90,000 rpm in a TLA100 rotor  (Beckman Instruments). Equal amounts of supernatants and pellets were  fractionated on 13% SDS-PAGE gels and visualized by autoradiography.  Results were quantified on a PhosphorImager using ImageQuant software  (STORM 860; Molecular Dynamics, Inc.) and on an IS2000 densitometer  using AlphaImager software.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>16460</offset><text>Molecular Modeling</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16479</offset><text>Images of actin and cofilin molecular models were generated on a Silicon  Graphics Indigo  workstation running Sybil software (Tripos Inc.). Coordinates for actin (file 1ATN) and yeast cofilin (file 1CFY) were retrieved from the Brookhaven database.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>16731</offset><text>Results</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>16739</offset><text>Identification and Sequence of Aip1p</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16776</offset><text>Aip1p was first identified as a 67-kD yeast protein that interacts with actin in the two-hybrid system (Amberg et al.,  1995a; GenBank accession number P46680) and is the first  discovered member of a family of conserved proteins (Fig.  1). Homologues of Aip1p have been identified in Schizosaccharomyces pombe, Physarum polycephalum (Matsumoto et al., 1998), Dictyostelium discoideum, Caenorhabditis elegans (where there are two homologues), Mus  musculus, and humans. Additionally, members of the  Aip1p family show weak homology to proteins that contain reiterated motifs called WD repeats. These repeats  were first identified in beta subunits of trimeric G-proteins  (Fong et al., 1986) and have since been found in proteins  with highly diverse functions. Members of the Aip1p family contain from four to eight WD repeats. </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>17604</offset><text>Two-Hybrid Interactions between Aip1p and Cofilin</text><annotation id="E10"><infon key="type">PPImention</infon><location offset="17604" length="49"/><text>Two-Hybrid Interactions between Aip1p and Cofilin</text></annotation><annotation id="E11"><infon key="type">PPIevidence</infon><location offset="17604" length="49"/><text>Two-Hybrid Interactions between Aip1p and Cofilin</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17654</offset><text>To identify additional Aip1p ligands we used a two-hybrid  construct of Aip1p fused to the GAL4 DBD (plasmid  pDAb189) to screen a large set of yeast actin interacting  proteins and cell polarity proteins fused to the GAL4 activation domain. Included in this set were clones encoding  AIP1, AIP2, AIP3, OYE2, SRV2, PFY1, COF1, BNR1,  LAS17, MNN10, ABP1, RVS167, BEM1, FUS1, and  SAC6. As can be seen in Fig. 2, we found that in addition  to actin, Aip1p also interacted with Cof1p (yeast cofilin).  These interactions are specific since no activation was observed between Aip1p and the transcription factor Snf4p  or between Aip1p and the actin cortical patch protein  Abp1p (data not shown). Furthermore, the Aip1p-actin  and Aip1p-cofilin two-hybrid interactions are reciprocal.  An apparent cofilin-cofilin interaction also was detected  but is likely the result of bridging through actin. The focus  of this study is the functional significance of the Aip1p- cofilin interaction. </text><annotation id="E12"><infon key="type">PPIevidence</infon><location offset="17654" length="241"/><text>To identify additional Aip1p ligands we used a two-hybrid  construct of Aip1p fused to the GAL4 DBD (plasmid  pDAb189) to screen a large set of yeast actin interacting  proteins and cell polarity proteins fused to the GAL4 activation domain.</text></annotation><annotation id="E13"><infon key="type">PPImention</infon><location offset="18039" length="112"/><text>As can be seen in Fig. 2, we found that in addition  to actin, Aip1p also interacted with Cof1p (yeast cofilin).</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>18647</offset><text>The Aip1p and Cofilin Binding Footprints on Actin</text><annotation id="E14"><infon key="type">PPImention</infon><location offset="18647" length="49"/><text>The Aip1p and Cofilin Binding Footprints on Actin</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>18697</offset><text>To obtain a structural framework for understanding the  functions of the Aip1p-actin and cofilin-actin interactions,  we used actin mutations (Wertman et al., 1992) in conjunction with the two-hybrid system to identify likely sites of  interaction for these proteins on actin. This approach was  described previously for the identification of the binding  footprint of Aip1p on actin (Amberg et al., 1995a) and was  repeated here to identify the binding footprint for cofilin  on actin (Fig. 3, A and B and Table II).  </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19221</offset><text>Yeast strain Y187, carrying a fusion of the Gal4p AD to  cofilin, was mated to strain Y190 containing plasmids encoding fusions of 35 actin mutants to the Gal4p DBD  (Amberg et al., 1995a). Diploids were replica plated on  3-AT medium to assess activation of the His3p two-hybrid  reporter (Fig. 3 A). Failure to grow on this medium indicates that the actin mutant contained in that strain is defective for the cofilin-actin interaction. This result suggests that the mutation may lie in or near the cofilin  binding site on actin. We discovered that eight actin mutants failed to interact with cofilin (Fig. 3 A). Of these  eight, five have thus far failed to interact with any actin-binding protein tested (act1-107, act1-130, act1-127, act1-128, and act1-108) and probably encode either unfolded or  unstable proteins. Therefore, nothing can be concluded  from these mutants. However, the remaining three mutants (act1-103, act1-106, and act1-126) display specific effects on the cofilin-actin interaction (Fig. 3 A).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20246</offset><text>The three mutations that specifically disrupt the cofilin- actin interaction are located in a small region of subdomain III on actin. Interestingly, these three mutations form  one-half of the Aip1p binding footprint (Amberg et al.,  1995a) that includes act1-109, act1-111, and act1-112, as  well as act1-103, act1-106, and act1-126 (Fig. 3 B). These  data are consistent with the model that Aip1p binding to  actin is facilitated by cofilin.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>20692</offset><text>The Aip1p and Actin Binding Footprints on Cofilin</text><annotation id="E15"><infon key="type">PPImention</infon><location offset="20692" length="49"/><text>The Aip1p and Actin Binding Footprints on Cofilin</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20742</offset><text>A large set of mutant alleles of cofilin has been constructed (Lappalainen et al., 1997) and the yeast cofilin  structure has been determined (Federov et al., 1997). This  presented us with the opportunity to use our two-hybrid  methodology to identify surfaces on cofilin required for its  interactions with Aip1p and actin. Toward this end, we  cloned the cofilin mutants into the two-hybrid activation  domain vector pACTII (gift of S. Elledge) and scored the  ability of these mutants to interact with Aip1p and actin.  Four cofilin mutants failed to interact with both actin and  Aip1p: cof1-9, cof1-16, cof1-17, and cof1-20. Two cofilin  mutants specifically failed to interact with actin: cof1-6 and  cof1-14. Three mutants, cof1-4, cof1-13, and cof1-22, failed  to interact with Aip1p but interacted well with actin.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21567</offset><text>We displayed the two-hybrid data on the molecular  model of cofilin (Fig. 3, C and D). In agreement with the in  vitro binding data of cofilin mutants to actin (Lappalainen  et al., 1997), the two-hybrid data identified a ridge that is  involved in the actin interaction (Fig. 3, red and purple in  B and C), on the edge of the disc-shaped cofilin protein. A  subset of the mutations that disrupted the cofilin-actin interaction constitute part of the Aip1p footprint on cofilin  (shown in purple in Fig. 3, C and D). A different set of mutations specifically affected cofilin interactions with Aip1p  and not actin (shown in blue). These data are consistent  with the model that Aip1p binding to cofilin is facilitated  by actin because, according to this model, disruption of the  cofilin-actin interaction would be predicted to also disrupt  the Aip1p-cofilin interaction. Overall, the footprinting  data suggest that there is a ternary complex between  Aip1p, cofilin, and actin, and that the members of this  complex make distinct contacts with each other.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>22635</offset><text>Synthetic Interactions with aip1Delta Mutants</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>22678</offset><text>The actin cytoskeleton consists of a large number of interacting components. Often the deletion of a gene encoding  one of these components does not in itself cause a readily  detectable phenotype. However, combinations of mutations can produce informative synthetic phenotypes that  suggest a shared or parallel function for the proteins involved (Adams et al., 1993). Deletion of the AIP1 gene  had no effect on cell growth on a variety of media at a variety of temperatures (data not shown). Therefore, we investigated its genetic interactions with mutations in genes  that encode other actin-binding proteins. </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23293</offset><text>First we crossed the aip1Delta strain to the collection of  clustered-charged-to-alanine mutants of COF1 (cof1-4,  cof1-5, cof1-6, cof1-7, cof1-10, cof1-11, cof1-12, cof1-13,  cof1-15, cof1-18, cof1-19, cof1-21, and cof1-22). The results  of these crosses are shown in Table II. The aip1Delta mutation  is synthetically lethal with cof1-5 and cof1-22, which are  both temperature sensitive for growth on their own and  show defects in actin turnover rates in vivo at the permissive temperature (Lappalainen and Drubin, 1997). In addition, the aip1Delta mutant is synthetically lethal with cof1-4,  which has no growth phenotype of its own but has actin organization defects as visualized by rhodamine-phalloidin  staining (Lappalainen et al., 1997). The aip1Delta mutant is  also synthetically temperature sensitive at 37 C with cof1-6,  which has no actin organization or growth phenotype on  its own (Lappalainen et al., 1997). We examined actin and  cofilin localization in the aip1Delta cof1-6 double mutant. At  the permissive temperature, the double mutant grows  slowly and has actin clumps in the mother cell. These  clumps stain with rhodamine-phalloidin, which binds specifically to F-actin and not G-actin. At the restrictive temperature, actin is depolarized, actin clumps are apparent,  and unbudded cells accumulate. Cofilin colocalizes with  the actin structures at both the permissive and restrictive  temperatures (data not shown).</text><annotation id="E16"><infon key="type">GIevidence</infon><location offset="23293" length="929"/><text>First we crossed the aip1Delta strain to the collection of  clustered-charged-to-alanine mutants of COF1 (cof1-4,  cof1-5, cof1-6, cof1-7, cof1-10, cof1-11, cof1-12, cof1-13,  cof1-15, cof1-18, cof1-19, cof1-21, and cof1-22). The results  of these crosses are shown in Table II. The aip1Delta mutation  is synthetically lethal with cof1-5 and cof1-22, which are  both temperature sensitive for growth on their own and  show defects in actin turnover rates in vivo at the permissive temperature (Lappalainen and Drubin, 1997). In addition, the aip1Delta mutant is synthetically lethal with cof1-4,  which has no growth phenotype of its own but has actin organization defects as visualized by rhodamine-phalloidin  staining (Lappalainen et al., 1997). The aip1Delta mutant is  also synthetically temperature sensitive at 37 C with cof1-6,  which has no actin organization or growth phenotype on  its own (Lappalainen et al., 1997).</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>24728</offset><text>We also determined if the aip1Delta mutation displayed  synthetic lethality with any of the viable actin-alanine scan  alleles of actin (act1-1, -101, 102, 104, 105, 108, 111, 113,  115, 116, 117, 119, 120, 121, 122, 123, 124, 125, 129, 132,  133, 136) and act1-159, which decreases rates of actin filament turnover in vivo and in vitro (Belmont et al., 1998).  When a yeast strain carrying the act1-159 mutation was  crossed to the aip1Delta strain, double mutant spores failed to  grow at 25 C. We also observed subtle synthetic growth  defects in double mutants containing the aip1Delta allele and  three other actin alleles: act1-133, act1-119, and act1-125  (data not shown). These three mutations are not located  near the Aip1p interaction interface on actin (Fig. 3), suggesting that the weak synthetic interactions are not a function of compromised Aip1p-actin interactions but of cumulative defects in cytoskeletal function.</text><annotation id="E17"><infon key="type">GIevidence</infon><location offset="24728" length="496"/><text>We also determined if the aip1Delta mutation displayed  synthetic lethality with any of the viable actin-alanine scan  alleles of actin (act1-1, -101, 102, 104, 105, 108, 111, 113,  115, 116, 117, 119, 120, 121, 122, 123, 124, 125, 129, 132,  133, 136) and act1-159, which decreases rates of actin filament turnover in vivo and in vitro (Belmont et al., 1998).  When a yeast strain carrying the act1-159 mutation was  crossed to the aip1Delta strain, double mutant spores failed to  grow at 25 C.</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25659</offset><text>Finally, we determined if the aip1Delta allele was synthetically lethal with deletion alleles of six other components  of the yeast cortical cytoskeleton: ABP1, SLA1, SLA2,  TWF1, CAP2, and SAC6. No clear synthetic lethality was  found. However, the sac6Delta, cap2Delta-1, and sla1Delta mutations  had slight synthetic growth defects in combination with  the aip1Delta allele (data not shown).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>26039</offset><text>Aip1p Localizes to Cortical Actin Patches</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>26081</offset><text>As a further test of the importance of the Aip1p-actin  and Aip1p-cofilin interactions in vivo, we sought to determine if Aip1p colocalizes with actin and cofilin. Toward this end, we generated antibodies to a GST-Aip1p  fusion protein. These antibodies specifically recognize a  67-kD protein on Western blots of wild-type (FY23)  yeast extract (Fig. 4 A, inset, lane 1) that is of the expected size based on the primary sequence of AIP1. This  band is absent from AIP1 deletion strain DAY53 (Fig. 4  A, inset, lane 2), but is restored when a low copy number vector carrying a 2.2-kb AIP1 genomic fragment  (pRB2251) is introduced into the deletion strain (Fig. 4  A, inset, lane 3). </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>26771</offset><text>Wild-type strain FY23x86 was stained with the anti-Aip1p antibodies (Fig. 4 B) and guinea pig antiactin antibodies (Fig. 4 A). Aip1p localized only to cortical actin  patches and was not detected along the actin cables. This  localization pattern is identical to that observed for cofilin  (Moon, 1993), but simultaneous colocalization of Aip1p  and cofilin was not possible, since both antibodies were  raised in rabbits. Since both Aip1p and cofilin appear to  be found in all actin cortical patches recognizable by antiactin antibodies, we presume that Aip1p and cofilin colocalize. Aip1p also localized diffusely throughout the cytoplasm and this cytoplasmic staining is not seen in the aip1Delta  strain (data not shown).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>27496</offset><text>The Aip1p-Actin Interaction Is Required for Aip1p  Localization to Cortical Patches</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27582</offset><text>To assess the importance and relevance of the Aip1p- actin two-hybrid interaction, we localized Aip1p in a strain  bearing actin mutations that disrupt the Aip1p-actin two-hybrid interaction. Fig. 5 A shows Aip1p localization in  the act1-111 strain TDS143. Aip1p was not detected in cortical patches in the mutant strain and there is an apparent  increase in the cytosolic Aip1p signal. The failure of Aip1p  to localize in this strain is not due to a loss in the ability of  cofilin to bind to actin (Fig. 5 B). Similarly, Aip1p localization to cortical patches in an act1-112 strain is severely  compromised (Fig. 5 C), whereas cofilin localization to  patches in this strain is not affected (Fig. 5 D). Aip1p was  well localized to cortical patches in act1-119, act1-132,  act1-124, and act1-125 strains (data not shown) indicating  that Aip1p mislocalization is not caused by generalized defects in the actin cytoskeleton. These results suggest that  Aip1p must bind to F-actin for stable association with cortical actin patches and is consistent with the two-hybrid  data suggesting that Aip1p contacts actin in the vicinity of  the act1-111 and act1-112 mutations. </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>28759</offset><text>Aip1p Localization in Cofilin Mutants</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>28797</offset><text>To test the importance of the Aip1p-cofilin interaction on  Aip1p localization, we examined Aip1p localization in viable cofilin mutants (Lappalainen et al., 1997). Both Aip1p  and cofilin were localized by indirect immunofluorescence  in strains bearing 14 different cof1 alleles: cof1-4, cof1-5,  cof1-6, cof1-7, cof1-8, cof1-10, cof1-11, cof1-12, cof1-13,  cof1-15, cof1-18, cof1-19, cof1-21, cof1-22, and a wild-type  congenic strain (Table II). The cells were grown at 25 C, a  permissive temperature for all the strains, before fixation.  Aip1p localized to patches in all of the cofilin mutants except the strain carrying the cof1-19 allele. Fig. 5 E shows  Aip1p localization in cof1-19 strain DDY1264. As was  seen with the act1-111 strain, Aip1p is lost completely  from the cortical patches in cof1-19 cells and there is an  apparent increase in the cytoplasmic pool of Aip1p. Double labeling of this strain with antiactin and anticofilin antibodies showed that Cof1-19p is associated with cortical  actin patches (Fig. 6). </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>29836</offset><text>The cof1-19 strain, like the aip1Delta strain, is viable and  has a wild-type growth phenotype. We have examined the  actin cytoskeleton in these strains and found no obvious  defects. However, both strains do appear to have slightly  aberrant cortical actin patches: they appear by rhodamine-phalloidin staining to be slightly larger or perhaps to  contain more F-actin (data not shown). In addition, the  cof1-19 cells have slightly depolarized actin patches and  misoriented actin cables.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>30325</offset><text>Aip1p is Required for Normal Cofilin Localization</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>30375</offset><text>To examine the role of Aip1p in cofilin localization, we  immunolocalized cofilin in the aip1Delta strain. Surprisingly,  cofilin localized not only to cortical patches but also to actin cables (Fig. 6 D). We confirmed colocalization of cofilin with actin cables by double staining with the guinea pig  antiactin antibody, as shown in Fig. 6 C. This result suggests that Aip1p is required to restrict cofilin to cortical actin patches in the yeast actin cytoskeleton.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>30840</offset><text>We asked if exclusive localization of cofilin to cortical  actin patches depends on localization of Aip1p to these  patches. To address this question, we examined cofilin localization in the cof1-19 mutant strain DDY1264, in which  Aip1p is localized in the cytoplasm. As can be seen in Fig.  6 F, Cof1-19p is localized to both the patches and the cables. Fig. 6 E shows the same cells stained with the antiactin antibody confirming association of Cof1-19p with the  actin cables. Though act1-111 and act1-112 mutants also  fail to localize Aip1p to actin patches (Fig. 5), we were unable to confirm that cofilin also localizes to actin cables in  these strains because their actin cytoskeletons are more  generally disrupted and cables are undetectable by antibody staining (data not shown).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31633</offset><text>We next asked if the localization of other proteins normally localized to the cortical actin patches was affected in  the aip1Delta strain. We found that immunolocalization of  Abp1p, fimbrin/Sac6p, and coronin/Crn1p was unaffected  by the absence of Aip1p (data not shown). This indicates  that the role of Aip1p in cofilin localization is specific and  not reflective of gross structural defects in the cortical  patches.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>32054</offset><text>Aip1p Increases the Extent of Cofilin-induced Depolymerization</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>32117</offset><text>To evaluate directly the functional and physical interaction between cofilin, actin, and Aip1p, we investigated the  effects that these proteins might have together in vitro.  Aip1p was expressed in yeast as a GST fusion protein under the control of the GAL promoter. GST-Aip1p was affinity-purified from extracts on glutathione-agarose beads,  cleaved from GST by thrombin digestion, and purified by  cation exchange chromatography. This protein has two  additional amino acids NH2-terminal to the primary sequence of Aip1p. No contaminants are apparent in the  preparation on overloaded (5 mug) Coomassie stained gels  (data not shown).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>32758</offset><text>To evaluate the interaction of Aip1p with F-actin at  steady state, we carried out cosedimentation assays with  2.5 muM prepolymerized yeast F-actin. For all of the assays  described here, after 20 min of coincubation the reaction is  at steady state as evaluated by light-scattering at 400 nm  (data not shown). Although a small proportion (5-10%) of  purified Aip1p sedimented in the absence of actin in these  assays, this amount did not perceptibly increase upon addition of actin (data not shown). Given the two-hybrid interaction of Aip1p and cofilin, it seemed possible that an  actin-Aip1p interaction might be mediated by cofilin. To  test this hypothesis, we performed the cosedimentation assay in the presence of recombinant cofilin, which binds to  F-actin and accelerates disassembly rates (increasing subunit turnover), but does not significantly change actin  polymer levels at steady state (Fig. 7 B, lanes 1 and 2).  Strikingly, in the presence of both Aip1p and cofilin, we  observed a dramatic shift of actin and cofilin from the pellet to the supernatant (Fig. 7 A, lane 2). This shift might be  explained by invoking a monomer sequestering model as  applies for twinfilin (Goode et al., 1998), a protein that  binds stoichiometrically to actin monomer, preventing nucleotide exchange and polymerization. We examined the  effects of stoichiometry on the Aip1p-dependent shift by  varying the concentration of Aip1p (0.012-2.5 muM; Fig. 7  A, lanes 2-6) or cofilin (0.12-2.5 muM; Fig. 7 B, lanes 3-7)  in cosedimentation assays with constant concentrations of  F-actin (2.5 muM). Intriguingly, though the shift into the supernatant showed a linear dependence on cofilin, it did not  require Aip1p at similar stoichiometry. In fact, a significant shift occurred at molar ratios of Aip1p/cofilin/actin as  low as 1:50:50 (Fig. 7 A, lane 4), and can even be seen at  molar ratios of Aip1p/cofilin/actin as low as 1:200:200 (Fig.  7 A, lane 6). </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>34731</offset><text>F-Actin Binding of Aip1p Is Facilitated by Cofilin</text><annotation id="E18"><infon key="type">PPImention</infon><location offset="34731" length="50"/><text>F-Actin Binding of Aip1p Is Facilitated by Cofilin</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>34782</offset><text>We used radiolabeled in vitro-translated Aip1p to evaluate binding to F-actin at a low concentration of Aip1p,  which would not promote net disassembly of the filaments.  The in vitro-translated Aip1p product sedimented with  actin filaments. This cosedimentation was abolished by addition of excess nonradiolabeled Aip1p or by dilution of  the sample, suggesting that the binding is specific (data not  shown). To establish the dependence of this binding on cofilin, we pelleted increasing concentrations of actin filaments with or without stoichiometric cofilin with in vitro- translated Aip1p. Aip1p cosedimented with the F-actin in  the absence of added cofilin, but addition of 1:1 cofilin increased the amount that cosedimented (Fig. 8 A). The  binding of Aip1p to cofilin-F-actin is saturatable with a Kd  of ~4 muM. Similar results were obtained by Western blot  analysis of identical experiments with purified Aip1p (data  not shown). We next examined how much added cofilin  was required to get the increased binding. The amount of  Aip1p cosedimenting with 7.5 muM F-actin falls off linearly  with cofilin concentration (Fig. 8 B). Aip1p cosedimentation with F-actin could be increased in the presence of cofilin either because cofilin creates more binding sites for  Aip1p, or because cofilin increases the affinity of Aip1p  for actin. To distinguish between these possibilities, we  added 15 and 45 nM purified Aip1p to 5 muM cofilin-saturated actin filaments (which is below the concentration  that saturates Aip1p binding) and ran the sedimentation  reaction. A threefold higher concentration of Aip1p increases the fraction of Aip1p cosedimenting with actin,  suggesting that Aip1p binding sites are not saturated, and  that the cofilin-dependent increase in binding reflects an  increased affinity of Aip1p for F-actin in the presence of  cofilin (data not shown). To determine stoichiometries  of these proteins in yeast cells, we estimated the ratio  of Aip1p/cofilin/actin in the cell by comparing immunoblots of whole-cell extracts and purified proteins of known  concentration (data not shown). Aip1p, cofilin, and actin  are each present in whole-cell extracts at a ratio of about  1:1:5 or 1:1:10. </text><annotation id="E19"><infon key="type">PPIevidence</infon><location offset="34782" length="169"/><text>We used radiolabeled in vitro-translated Aip1p to evaluate binding to F-actin at a low concentration of Aip1p,  which would not promote net disassembly of the filaments.</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>37016</offset><text>Discussion</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>37027</offset><text>Aip1p-Cofilin-Actin Interactions Suggest a Ternary Complex</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>37090</offset><text>Aip1p was originally identified by its two-hybrid interaction with actin (Amberg et al., 1995a). Further two-hybrid  analysis revealed an interaction between Aip1p and cofilin  (Fig. 2) raising the possibility that actin, Aip1p, and cofilin  might form a ternary complex. The existence of such a ternary complex is supported by evidence that Aip1p and cofilin are dependent on each other and on actin for their  correct localization in vivo (Fig. 5). Binding experiments  with purified proteins also support an Aip1p-cofilin-actin  complex (Fig. 8). Binding of purified or in vitro-translated  Aip1p to F-actin is concentration-dependent and increases  at high ratios of cofilin/actin. Since cofilin is a contaminant  in yeast actin preparations, despite efforts to deplete it  (~1 muM/100 muM actin), we cannot rule out the possibility  that contaminating native cofilin is responsible for the  baseline binding to F-actin in the absence of added recombinant cofilin. Thus, it is possible that Aip1p binding to  F-actin is strictly cofilin-dependent. We were unable to  show a direct interaction between Aip1p and cofilin and/ or G-actin by native gel shift or by cosedimentation with  GST-Aip1p, further suggesting that Aip1p interacts  with cofilin on F-actin.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>38364</offset><text>A large set of mutations in both actin (Wertman et al.,  1992) and cofilin (Lappalainen et al., 1997) was used in  conjunction with the two-hybrid system to identify regions  of actin and cofilin involved in the Aip1p interaction (Fig.  3). Those data that describe the cofilin-actin interface appear sound since they agree with similar studies using biochemical (Lappalainen et al., 1997), modeling (Wriggers  et al., 1998), and structural (Amy McGough, personal  communication) approaches. The binding footprint (as obtained by two-hybrid analysis) for Aip1p on the surface of  actin (Fig. 3 B, blue and red) partially overlaps with the  cofilin binding site (red). Similarly, the footprints of Aip1p  and actin on cofilin overlap as four cofilin mutants were  specifically defective for both Aip1p and actin binding.  Though overlapping interaction interfaces are consistent  with both competitive interactions and a ternary complex,  we favor the latter model because it is consistent with the  localization and in vitro binding data discussed above.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>39421</offset><text>While most of our structural data can be incorporated  into a coherent model for interaction in a ternary complex,  there were several discrepancies between the biochemical  and two-hybrid data. First, only by two-hybrid assay was  cof1-9 defective for binding to actin. Additionally, although cof1-6 has a wild-type growth phenotype, by two-hybrid analysis it appears to be completely defective for  actin binding. This interaction has not been tested biochemically. These discrepancies may be an artifact resulting from the fusion to Gal4p in the two-hybrid system. Alternatively, the cofilin-actin two-hybrid interaction might  be subtly different than that observed in vitro with purified components. Note that cof1-19 is the only cofilin mutant that is defective for Aip1p localization, but it appears  to interact well with both Aip1p and actin by two-hybrid  analysis. This cofilin mutant may interact well with actin  and Aip1p in the two-hybrid complex but have subtly altered binding properties in vivo.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>40435</offset><text>In Vivo Interactions Support a Role for Aip1p in  Promoting Actin Dynamics</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>40510</offset><text>Though the AIP1 deletion mutant has no obvious phenotype on its own, allele-specific synthetic lethality was observed between aip1Delta and act1-159, cof1-4, cof1-5, cof1-22,  and cof1-6 (at 37 C). These results suggest that in the double mutants, a common function is compromised enough  that cell viability is lost. Because act1-159, cof1-5, and  cof1-22 have all been shown to decrease the rate of F-actin  disassembly in vivo (Lappalainen and Drubin, 1997;  Belmont and Drubin, 1998), we postulate that Aip1p  also promotes actin filament turnover. This conclusion is  supported by our biochemical studies of Aip1p that demonstrate that it causes cofilin-dependent actin filament disassembly (Fig. 7). Note that Cof1-22p has defects in actin  binding in vitro, but that Cof1-5p does not (Lappalainen et  al., 1997), suggesting that the synthetic interaction is not  simply a function of compromised actin binding by cofilin.  The cofilin-actin interaction has not been tested biochemically for cof1-4 or for cof1-6.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>41530</offset><text>Specific sorting of cofilin to cortical patches but not cytoplasmic cables is lost in aip1Delta (Fig. 6 C) and cof1-19  (Fig. 6 E) strains. One model that could explain these results in terms of the in vitro effects of Aip1p on actin filaments assumes that two populations of actin cables, one  cofilin-bound and one tropomyosin-bound, form in yeast  cells. Cofilin-bound cables would undergo net depolymerization in the presence of Aip1p, as occurs for purified actin filaments in vitro. Tropomyosin, which is localized to  actin cables (Liu and Bretscher, 1989), can compete for  cofilin binding sites on actin (Bernstein and Bamburg,  1982). Thus, tropomyosin would stabilize a subset of cables against Aip1p-cofilin depolymerization and these  would go on to be the normal cables visualized in cells. In  the aip1Delta strain or in a cofilin mutant that mislocalizes  Aip1p (cof1-19), Aip1p would not be able to function synergistically with cofilin to destabilize the filaments, and  both cofilin-bound and tropomyosin-bound populations of  filaments would be maintained. In support of this model,  cofilin also localizes to rare actin cables in act1-159 tpm1Delta  and act1-159 mdm20Delta double mutant strains (Belmont et  al., 1998), which would be predicted to have hyperstable  F-actin structures that would not be readily disassembled  by cofilin-Aip1p.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>42887</offset><text>The aip1Delta allele was also found to enhance the defects  observed in specific actin mutants (act1-119, act1-125, and  act1-133) and in null alleles of genes encoding several  components of the cortical actin cytoskeleton (Sac6p,  Sla1p, and Cap2p). We believe that these double mutants  most likely suffer from a general, cumulative derangement  of the actin cytoskeleton, a conclusion that further supports that the actin cytoskeleton is affected in the aip1Delta  strain.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>43358</offset><text>The Aip1p-Cofilin-Actin Complex Promotes  Disassembly In Vitro</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>43425</offset><text>We demonstrated that Aip1p causes cofilin-mediated actin filament depolymerization in vitro (Fig. 7). Interestingly, we discovered that Aip1p can induce cofilin-mediated actin filament depolymerization at stoichiometries as  low as 1:50:50 Aip1/actin/cofilin. On the other hand, cofilin must be present at a 1:1 ratio with actin for optimal  Aip1p-mediated activation of depolymerization.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>43814</offset><text>Though we were able to detect concentration-dependent F-actin cosedimentation of Aip1p at a low molar  ratio with actin (by Western blot analysis or using in vitro-translated Aip1p), we were unable to detect cosedimentation at higher Aip1p/actin ratios. One hypothesis  that explains these results is that Aip1p saturates binding  at a low stoichiometry with F-actin. A second hypothesis is  that high ratios of cofilin/actin are required for Aip1p  binding, but that at high concentrations of Aip1p, net depolymerization prevents cosedimentation of Aip1p with  actin. A model that is consistent with substoichiometric or  cofilin-dependent filament binding, net filament depolymerization, and the two-hybrid footprinting data is that  Aip1p enhances the weak severing activity of cofilin (MacIver et al. 1991; McGough et al., 1997).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>44650</offset><text>Aip1p is the first protein aside from actin and LIM-kinase to show a physical interaction with cofilin. The fact  that Aip1p is highly conserved in eukaryotes suggests that  it may be a cofactor for cofilin activity in all eukaryotic  cells. Though the mechanistic details of these interactions  remain to be elucidated fully, our biochemical data demonstrate clearly that Aip1p stimulates cofilin-mediated actin filament disassembly and our genetic and cell biological data provides powerful evidence for the relevance of  this activity in vivo.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>45197</offset><text>Figures and Tables</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>45216</offset><text>Saccharomyces cerevisiae Strains </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table</infon><offset>45250</offset><text>   Name  Genotype  Source   FY23  a ura3-52 leu2Delta1 trp1Delta63  Winston et al., 1995  FY86  alpha ura3-52 leu2Delta1 his3Delta200  Winston et al., 1995  FY23x86  a/alpha ura3-52/ura3-52 leu2Delta1/leu2Delta1 trp1Delta63/TRP1 HIS3/his3Delta200  This work  Y187  alpha gal4 gal80 his3 trp1-901 ade2-101 ura3-52 leu2-3,112 GAL--lacZ  Bai and Elledge, 1996  Y190  a gal4 gal80 his3 trp1-901 ade2-101 ura3-52 leu2-3,112 URA3::GAL--lacZ LYS2::GAL--HIS3cyhr  Bai and Elledge, 1996  DAY30  a ura3-52 leu2Delta1 trp1Delta63 aip1-Delta1::URA3  This work  DAY52  a ura3-52 leu2Delta1 trp1Delta63 his3Delta200 aip1-Delta1::TRP1  This work  DAY53  a ura3-52 leu2Delta1 trp1Delta63 his3Delta200 aip1-Delta1::TRP1  This work  DBY6527  a ura3-52 leu2Delta1 trp1Delta63 his3Delta200 aip1-Delta1::URA3  Amberg et al., 1995b  DBY6529  a ura3-52 leu2Delta1 trp1Delta63 his3Delta200 aip1-Delta1::LEU2  Amberg et al., 1995b  DBY6531  alpha ura3-52 leu2Delta1 trp1Delta63 his3Delta200 aip1-Delta1::TRP1  Amberg et al., 1995b  DDY130  a ura3-52 leu2-3,112 his3Delta200 lys2-801    DDY496  alpha leu2-3,112 ura3-52 sla2-Delta1::URA3    DDY319  a sac6-Delta1::LEU2 his3Delta200 leu2-3,112 lys2-801 ura3-52    DDY321  a abp1-Delta1::LEU2 his3Delta200 leu2-3,112 ura3-52    DDY760  a sla1-Delta1::LEU2 leu2-3,112 ura3-52 ade2-1 ade3    TDS143  a ura3-52 leu2-3,112 his3Delta200 tub2-210 act1-111::HIS3 ade4  Wertman et al., 1992  TDS150  a ura3-52 leu2-3,112 his3Delta200 tub2-210 act1-119::HIS3 ade4  Wertman et al., 1992  TDS156  a ura3-52 leu2-3,112 his3Delta200 tub2-210 act1-125::HIS3 ade4  Wertman et al., 1992  TDS363  a ura3-52 leu2-3,112 his3Delta200 tub2-210 act1-133::HIS3 ade2-101  Wertman et al., 1992  TDS167  a ura3-52 leu2-3,112 his3Delta200 tub2-210 ACT1::HIS3 ade4  Wertman et al., 1992  DDY355  a ura3-52 leu2-3,112 his3Delta200 tub2-210 act1-112::HIS3 ade4 ade2-101 cry1    DDY582  a ura3-1 leu2-3,112 trp1-1 his3-11,15 ade2-101 cap2-Delta1::HIS3    DDY1252  alpha ura3-52 his3Delta200 lys2-801 COF1::LEU2    DDY1253  alpha ura3-52 his3Delta200 lys2-801 cof1-4    DDY1254  alpha ura3-52 his3Delta200 lys2-801 cof1-5    DDY1255  alpha ura3-52 his3Delta200 lys2-801 cof1-6    DDY1256  alpha ura3-52 his3Delta200 lys2-801 cof1-7    DDY1257  alpha ura3-52 his3Delta200 lys2-801 cof1-10    DDY1258  alpha ura3-52 his3Delta200 lys2-801 cof1-8    DDY1259  alpha ura3-52 his3Delta200 lys2-801 cof1-11    DDY1260  alpha ura3-52 his3Delta200 lys2-801 cof1-12    DDY1261  alpha ura3-52 his3Delta200 lys2-801 cof1-13    DDY1262  alpha ura3-52 his3Delta200 lys2-801 cof1-15    DDY1263  alpha ura3-52 his3Delta200 lys2-801 cof1-18    DDY1264  alpha ura3-52 his3Delta200 lys2-801 cof1-19    DDY1265  alpha ura3-52 his3Delta200 lys2-801 cof1-21    DDY1266  alpha ura3-52 his3Delta200 lys2-801 cof1-22    DDY1435  a ura3-52 leu2-3,112 his3Delta200 ade2-101 twf1Delta::URA3  Goode et al., 1998  DDY1492  a ura3-52 leu2-3,112 his3Delta200 tub2-101 act1-159::HIS3  Belmont et al., 1998</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>47964</offset><text>Sequence alignment of Aip1p and its homologues. Identities are boxed. Sequences were aligned with ClustalW 1.7 and analyzed in Seqvu 1.1 (Garvan Research Institute). Identity is assigned if 4 of 6 residues at a position are identical. SwissProt accession  numbers for the given sequences are the following: S. cerevisiae (P46680), S. pombe (O14301), P. polycephalum (P90587), D. discoideum (P54686), C. elegans (Q11176), and Homo sapiens (GenBank AF020056).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>48422</offset><text>Two-hybrid interactions of Aip1p. A GAL4-based two-hybrid system was used to assess interactions between Aip1p and  several proteins involved in cytoskeleton function and cell polarity. Displayed here is a representative sampling of that data. The  two-hybrid plasmids were cointroduced by mating strain Y190,  carrying plasmids encoding fusions to the GAL4 DBD, and strain  Y187, carrying plasmids encoding fusions to the GAL4 AD. The  resulting diploids were selected and replica plated to medium  containing 100 mM 3-AT.</text><annotation id="E20"><infon key="type">PPImention</infon><location offset="48422" length="33"/><text>Two-hybrid interactions of Aip1p.</text></annotation><annotation id="E21"><infon key="type">PPIevidence</infon><location offset="48422" length="33"/><text>Two-hybrid interactions of Aip1p.</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>48946</offset><text>Two-hybrid analysis of the structure of the Aip1p-cofilin-actin complex. Two-hybrid analysis was performed between 36 actin alleles fused to the GAL4 DBD and cofilin fused to the GAL4 AD. Activation of the HIS3 two-hybrid reporter was assessed on medium containing 50 mM 3-AT at 25 C (A). A model of the actin monomer is shown in B. In red are the amino acids altered by mutations  that disrupt both the actin-cofilin and actin-Aip1p two-hybrid interactions. In blue are the amino acids altered by mutations that disrupt only the actin-Aip1p interaction. Marked with green are those mutations that had no effect on either interaction. The allele numbers of disruptive mutations are indicated. Displayed in C and D are two views, 180  apart, of yeast cofilin. Mutations that disrupted  both the cofilin-actin and the cofilin-Aip1p two-hybrid interactions are indicated in purple. Mutations that disrupted the cofilin-actin  interaction alone are indicated in red. Mutations that disrupted the cofilin-Aip1p interaction alone are indicated in blue, and mutations  that had no effect on either the cofilin-actin or cofilin-Aip1 interactions are shown in green.</text><annotation id="E22"><infon key="type">PPImention</infon><location offset="48946" length="72"/><text>Two-hybrid analysis of the structure of the Aip1p-cofilin-actin complex.</text></annotation><annotation id="E23"><infon key="type">PPIevidence</infon><location offset="48946" length="72"/><text>Two-hybrid analysis of the structure of the Aip1p-cofilin-actin complex.</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>50128</offset><text>Genetic and Physical Interactions within the Aip1p-Cof1p-Act1p Complex </text><annotation id="E24"><infon key="type">PPImention</infon><location offset="50128" length="70"/><text>Genetic and Physical Interactions within the Aip1p-Cof1p-Act1p Complex</text></annotation><annotation id="E25"><infon key="type">GImention</infon><location offset="50128" length="70"/><text>Genetic and Physical Interactions within the Aip1p-Cof1p-Act1p Complex</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">table</infon><offset>50200</offset><text>   Allele  Phen.  Two-hybrid interactions  Genetic interactions  Localization  With actin  With Aip1p Aip1p localization  Cof1p localization   COF1  WT  +++  +++  na  Cortical patches  Cortical patches   cof1-4  wt  +++  -  SL w/aip1Delta  Cortical patches  Cortical patches  cof1-5  ts  +++  +++  SL w/aip1Delta  Cortical patches  Cortical patches  cof1-6  wt  -  ++  ts w/aip1Delta  Cortical patches  Cortical patches  cof1-7  nd  +++  +++  nd  nd  nd  cof1-8  ts  ++  +  nd  Cortical patches  Cortical patches  cof1-9  lt  -  -  nd  nd  nd  cof1-10  wt  +++  +++  None  Cortical patches  Cortical patches  cof1-11  wt  +++  +++  None  Cortical patches  Cortical patches  cof1-12  wt  +++  +++  None  Cortical patches  Cortical patches  cof1-13  wt  +++  -  None  Cortical patches  Cortical patches  cof1-14  lt  -  ++  nd  nd  nd  cof1-15  wt  ++  +++  None  Cortical patches  Cortical patches  cof1-16  lt  -  -  nd  nd  nd  cof1-17  lt  -  -  nd  nd  nd  cof1-18  wt  +++  +++  nd  Cortical patches  Cortical patches  cof1-19  wt  ++  ++  None  Cytosolic  Patches and cables  cof1-20  lt  -  -  None  nd  nd  cof1-21  wt  +++  +++  nd  Cortical patches  Cortical patches  cof1-22  ts  ++  -  SL w/aip1Delta  Cortical patches  Cortical patches  aip1Delta  wt  na  na  SL w/act1-159  na  Patches and cables  act1-111  ts  na  -  na  Cytosolic  Patches  act1-112  ts  na  -  na  Mostly cytosolic  Patches</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>51622</offset><text>Abbreviations: wt, wild-type; ts, temperature sensitive; lt, lethal; na, not applicable; SL, synthetic lethal; nd, no data. Genetic interactions were determined from dissection of eight  tetrads derived from two different complex heterozygotes. The tetrads were incubated at 25 C and the genotypes of the spore strains were inferred from marker segregation. None  of the double mutants were viable for combinations scored as showing synthetic lethality. Double mutants that were viable at 25 C were grown at a variety of temperatures and  compared in parallel with sibling spores from the same tetrads (including single mutants) to determine temperature sensitivity. 27 of 29 aip1Deltacof1-6 isolates were temperature sensitive at 37 C.             </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>52373</offset><text>Aip1p localizes to cortical actin patches. Immunofluorescence was performed on wild-type strain FY23x86 using a guinea pig  antiactin antibody (A) and affinity-purified anti-Aip1 antibody (B). Western blot of yeast protein extracts using anti-Aip1p rabbit antiserum (insert in A). The amount of protein loaded was normalized to the number of cells from which extract was prepared. Wild-type  strain FY23 (lane 1), AIP1 deletion strain DAY53 (lane 2). DAY53 carrying plasmid pRB2251 with a minimal genomic subclone of the  AIP1 locus (lane 3).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>52917</offset><text>Aip1p localization to cortical patches requires actin  and cofilin. Immunofluorescence was performed on strain  TDS143 (act1-111) grown at 25 C (A and B), strain DDY355  grown at 37 C (act1-112; C and D), and strain DDY1264 (cof1-19)  grown at 25 C (E) using affinity-purified anti-Aip1p antibody (A,  C, and E), affinity-purified rabbit anticofilin antibody (B and D),  and a fluorescein-conjugated goat anti-rabbit secondary antibody.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>53359</offset><text>Selective localization of cofilin to cortical patches is dependent on Aip1p. Immunofluorescence was performed on wild-type  strain DDY1252 (A and B), aip1Delta strain DAY30 (C and D), and on cof1-19 strain DDY1264 (E and F) using guinea pig antiactin antibodies and a rhodamine-conjugated goat anti-guinea pig secondary antibody (A, C, and E), and anticofilin antibodies in conjunction  with an FITC-conjugated goat anti-rabbit secondary antibody (B, D, and F).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>53822</offset><text>Aip1p enhances  the extent and rate of cofilin-mediated actin dynamics. 2.5  muM actin filaments were incubated with varying concentrations of cofilin and/or  Aip1p. Coomassie stained  gels and accompanying quantification show the dependence of the Aip1p-cofilin  interaction on Aip1p concentration (A) and on cofilin  concentration (B).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>54162</offset><text>Aip1p actin binding is enhanced by cofilin. Actin filaments were assembled and incubated with cofilin and in vitro- translated Aip1p. A shows binding curves with and without  added cofilin. B shows cosedimentation of Aip1p with 7.5 muM actin at various concentrations of cofilin.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>54444</offset><text>Abbreviations used in this paper</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>54477</offset><text>AD</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>54480</offset><text>activation domain</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>54498</offset><text>Aip1</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>54503</offset><text>actin interacting protein 1</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>54531</offset><text>3-AT</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>54536</offset><text>3,5-amino-triazole</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>54555</offset><text>DBD</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>54559</offset><text>DNA binding domain</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>54578</offset><text>GST</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>54582</offset><text>glutathione-S-transferase</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>54608</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">934</infon><infon key="lpage">945</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Adams;given-names:AE</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Pringle;given-names:JR</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">6365931</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">98</infon><infon key="year">1984</infon><offset>54619</offset><text>Relationship of actin and tubulin distribution to bud growth in wild-type and morphogenic-mutant Saccharomyces  cerevisiae. </text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">459</infon><infon key="lpage">468</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Adams;given-names:AE</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Cooper;given-names:JA</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Drubin;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8334302</infon><infon key="source">Mol Biol Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">4</infon><infon key="year">1993</infon><offset>54744</offset><text>Unexpected combinations of null mutations in genes encoding the actin cytoskeleton are lethal in yeast</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">3259</infon><infon key="lpage">3262</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Amberg;given-names:DC</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9843567</infon><infon key="source">Mol Biol Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>54847</offset><text>Three-dimensional imaging of the yeast actin-cytoskeleton through the budding cell-cycle</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">28</infon><infon key="lpage">35</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Amberg;given-names:DC</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Basart;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Botstein;given-names:D</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">7719850</infon><infon key="source">Nat Struct Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2</infon><infon key="year">1995a</infon><offset>54936</offset><text>Defining protein interactions with yeast actin in vivo</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1275</infon><infon key="lpage">1280</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Amberg;given-names:DC</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Botstein;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Beasley;given-names:EM</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8553698</infon><infon key="source">Yeast</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">1995b</infon><offset>54991</offset><text>Precise gene disruption  in Saccharomyces cerevisiaeby double fusion PCR</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">331</infon><infon key="lpage">347</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bai;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Elledge;given-names:SJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8791622</infon><infon key="source">Methods Enzymol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">273</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>55064</offset><text>Gene identification using the yeast two-hybrid system</text></passage><passage><infon key="citation">Becker, D.M., and L. Guarante. 1991. High-efficiency transformation of yeast  by electroporation. In Guide to Yeast Genetics and Molecular Biology. Vol.  194. C. Guthrie and G.R. Fink, editors. Academic Press, Inc., San Diego,  CA. 182-186.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>55118</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1289</infon><infon key="lpage">1299</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Belmont;given-names:LD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Drubin;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9732289</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">142</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>55119</offset><text>The yeast V159N actin mutant reveals roles for actin dynamics in vivo</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">8</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bernstein;given-names:BW</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bamburg;given-names:JR</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">6890875</infon><infon key="source">Cell Motil</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2</infon><infon key="year">1982</infon><offset>55189</offset><text>Tropomyosin binding to F-actin protects the F-actin from disassembly by brain actin-depolymerizing-factor (ADF)</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2551</infon><infon key="lpage">2561</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Drubin;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Miller;given-names:KG</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Botstein;given-names:D</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">3060468</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">107</infon><infon key="year">1988</infon><offset>55301</offset><text>Yeast actin-binding proteins: evidence for a role in morphogenesis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">366</infon><infon key="lpage">369</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Federov;given-names:AA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lappalainen;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Federov;given-names:EV</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Drubin;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Almo;given-names:SC</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9145106</infon><infon key="source">Nat Struct Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">4</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>55368</offset><text>Structure determination of yeast cofilin</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2162</infon><infon key="lpage">2166</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Fong;given-names:HK</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hurley;given-names:JB</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hopkins;given-names:RS</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Miake-Lye;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Johnson;given-names:MS</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Doolittle;given-names:RF</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Simon;given-names:MI</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">3083416</infon><infon key="source">Proc Natl Acad Sci USA</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">83</infon><infon key="year">1986</infon><offset>55409</offset><text>Repetitive segmental structure of the transducin beta subunit: homology with the CDC4 gene and identification of related mRNAs</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">723</infon><infon key="lpage">733</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Goode;given-names:BL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Drubin;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lappalainen;given-names:P</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9700161</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">142</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>55536</offset><text>Regulation of the cortical actin cytoskeleton in budding yeast by twinfilin, a ubiquitous actin monomer-sequestering protein</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">83</infon><infon key="lpage">98</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Goode;given-names:BL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wong;given-names:JJ</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Butty;given-names:A-C</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Peter;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:McCormack;given-names:AL</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Yates;given-names:JR</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Drubin;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Barnes;given-names:G</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9885246</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">144</infon><infon key="year">1999</infon><offset>55661</offset><text>Coronin promotes rapid assembly and cross-linking of actin filaments and may link the actin and microtubule cytoskeletons in yeast</text></passage><passage><infon key="citation">Harlow, E., and D. Lane. 1988. Antibodies: A Laboratory Manual. Cold Spring  Harbor Laboratory Press, Cold Spring Harbor, New York. 726 pp.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>55792</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">635</infon><infon key="lpage">644</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Holtzman;given-names:DA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Yang;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Drubin;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8335689</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">122</infon><infon key="year">1993</infon><offset>55793</offset><text>Synthetic-lethal interactions  identify two novel genes, SLA1 and SLA2, that control membrane cytoskeleton assembly in Saccharomyces cerevisiae. </text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">423</infon><infon key="lpage">432</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Holtzman;given-names:DA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wertman;given-names:KF</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Drubin;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8034743</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">126</infon><infon key="year">1994</infon><offset>55939</offset><text>Mapping actin surfaces required for functional interactions in vivo</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">78</infon><infon key="lpage">82</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lappalainen;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Drubin;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9214506</infon><infon key="source">Nature</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">388</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>56007</offset><text>Cofilin promotes rapid actin filament turnover in vivo</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">5520</infon><infon key="lpage">5530</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lappalainen;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Federov;given-names:EV</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Federov;given-names:AA</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Almo;given-names:SC</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Drubin;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9312011</infon><infon key="source">EMBO (Eur Mol Biol Organ) J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>56062</offset><text>Essential functions and actin-binding surfaces of yeast cofilin revealed by systematic mutagenesis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">233</infon><infon key="lpage">242</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Liu;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bretscher;given-names:A</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">2649250</infon><infon key="source">Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">57</infon><infon key="year">1989</infon><offset>56161</offset><text>Disruption of the single tropomyosin gene in yeast results in the disappearance of actin cables from the cytoskeleton</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1611</infon><infon key="lpage">1620</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:MacIver;given-names:SK</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zot;given-names:HG</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Pollard;given-names:TD</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">1757465</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">115</infon><infon key="year">1991</infon><offset>56279</offset><text>Characterization of actin filament severing by actophorin from Acanthamoeba castellani. </text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">326</infon><infon key="lpage">331</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Matsumoto;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ogawa;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kasakura;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Shimada;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Mitsui;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Maruya;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Isohata;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Yahara;given-names:I</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Murakami-Murofushi;given-names:K</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9685722</infon><infon key="source">J Biochem</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">124</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>56368</offset><text>A novel 66-kDa  stress protein p66, associated with the process of cyst formation of Physarum  polycephalum is a Physarumhomologue of a yeast actin-interacting protein AIP1</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">771</infon><infon key="lpage">781</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:McGough;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Pope;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chiu;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Weeds;given-names:A</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9265645</infon><infon key="source">J  Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">138</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>56541</offset><text>Cofilin changes the twist of F-actin: implications for actin filament dynamics and cellular function</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">715</infon><infon key="lpage">723</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Mitchell;given-names:DA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Marshall;given-names:TK</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Deschenes;given-names:RJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8368005</infon><infon key="source">Yeast</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">1993</infon><offset>56642</offset><text>Vectors for the inducible overexpression of glutathione S-transferase fusion proteins in yeast</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">421</infon><infon key="lpage">435</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Moon;given-names:AL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Janmey;given-names:PA</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Louie;given-names:KA</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Drubin;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8421056</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">120</infon><infon key="year">1993</infon><offset>56737</offset><text>Cofilin is an essential component of the yeast cortical cytoskeleton</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1423</infon><infon key="lpage">1431</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Moon;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Drubin;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8589446</infon><infon key="source">Mol Biol Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">6</infon><infon key="year">1995</infon><offset>56806</offset><text>The ADF/cofilin proteins: stimulus-responsive modulators of actin dynamics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">381</infon><infon key="lpage">391</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Mulholland;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Preuss;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Moon;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wong;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Drubin;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Botstein;given-names:D</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8163554</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">125</infon><infon key="year">1994</infon><offset>56881</offset><text>Ultrastructure of the yeast actin cytoskeleton and its association with the plasma membrane</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">371</infon><infon key="lpage">373</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Peranen;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Rikkonen;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hyvonen;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Kaariainenen;given-names:L</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8660525</infon><infon key="source">Anal Biochem</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">236</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>56973</offset><text>T7 vectors  with a modified T7lac promoter for expression of proteins in Escherichia  coli. </text></passage><passage><infon key="citation">Pringle, J.R., A.E.M. Adams, D.G. Drubin, and B.K. Haarer. 1991. Immunofluorescence methods for yeast. In Guide to Yeast Genetics and Molecular Biology. Vol. 194. C. Guthrie and G.R. Fink, editors. Academic Press, Inc.,  San Diego. 565-601.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>57066</offset></passage><passage><infon key="citation">Rose, M.D., F.M. Winston, and P. Hieter. 1989. Methods in Yeast Genetics: A  Laboratory Course Manual. Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press, Cold  Spring Harbor, NY. 198 pp.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>57067</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">31</infon><infon key="lpage">40</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Smith;given-names:DB</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Johnson;given-names:KS</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">3047011</infon><infon key="source">Gene</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">67</infon><infon key="year">1988</infon><offset>57068</offset><text>Single-step purification of polypeptides  expressed in Escherichia colias fusions with glutathione S-transferase</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">337</infon><infon key="lpage">350</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wertman;given-names:KF</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Drubin;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Botstein;given-names:D</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">1427032</infon><infon key="source">Genetics</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">132</infon><infon key="year">1992</infon><offset>57181</offset><text>Systematic mutational  analysis of the yeast ACT1gene</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">53</infon><infon key="lpage">55</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Winston;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dollard;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Rioupero-Hovasse;given-names:LL</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">7762301</infon><infon key="source">Yeast</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">1995</infon><offset>57235</offset><text>Construction of a  set of convenient Saccharomyces cerevisiaestrains that are isogenic to S288C</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">921</infon><infon key="lpage">932</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wriggers;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tang;given-names:JX</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Azuma;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Marks;given-names:PW</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Janmey;given-names:PA</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9753544</infon><infon key="source">J Mol Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">282</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>57331</offset><text>Cofilin and gelsolin segment-1: molecular dynamics simulation and biochemical analysis predict a similar actin binding mode</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>57455</offset><text>Research in D.C. Amberg's laboratory was supported by National Institutes of Health (NIH) grant GM56189. Research in D.G. Drubin's laboratory was supported by NIH grant GM42759 and A.A. Rodal was supported by a Howard Hughes Medical Institute Predoctoral Fellowship.</text></passage></document></collection>
